wshbang - #! support for Windows

Description
    🪟❗ wshbang is a batch script that allows Windows users to use the #!
    interpreter directive common to *nix systems. That is, instead of
    associating all files with a given file extension a single interpreter,
    files will be able to define their own interpreter in via a #! header. More
    importantly, options/arguments and standard input should work as expected,
    which is frequently not the case given Windows association handling.

Associations
    wshbang must still be associated with given file extensions. From then on,
    Windows invokes wshbang to interpret the file, which in turn passes control
    to the interpreter of choice. Association is handled differently in recent
    and older versions of Windows. Instructions for each is given below; these
    do not conflict, try both if you are uncertain which is appropriate.

    Windows ≥ 10
        Starting in Windows 10, programs are no longer able to alter file
        associations; users may do so in settings. The simplest way to do so is
        to right-click your target file & select "Open with"; navigate to /
        select wshbang & check the "Always use..." box to set the default from
        now on.
    Windows < 10
        In earlier versions of Windows, wshbang may set associations directly.
        The `-a [extension]` option described below will prompt for elevation
        (per UAC settings) & set associations appropriately.

Format
    wshbang expects `#!` as first two bytes of the interpreted file, followed by
    a path to the executable & up to one option. Whitespace is not permitted
    before the `#!`, but is optional & permitted between it and the executable
    path. Furthermore, it delimits the interpreter & option; it is not allowed
    in the executables path.

Behavior
    If the first two bytes found are not `#!`, wshbang raises an openwith
    prompt as common for files with no association.
    Windows-native paths are useable directly: if the interpreter term is found
    in the working directory or the search path (%PATH%), it is invoked
    directly.
    Path searching translates across Unix/Windows: if the executable path is
    `/usr/bin/env` or `/bin/env`, an executable must follow as an option to
    `env` (or an error is raised). This executable is invoked directly. Note the
    shell will parse the %PATHEXT% variable to determine viable extensions; eg.
    Unix's `python` will ultimately translate to Windows' `python.exe`.
    Full Unix paths are mapped to Windows paths: The directory containing this
    script is searched for a file named `unix_windows.tab`, a tab-delimited file
    mapping from Unix to Windows executables. Rows are parsed in sequence; if
    the Unix executable is matched, the windows executable will be path searched
    (%PATH%, %PATHEXT% apply). If a suitable executable is not found, the user
    is prompted to enter one. Note: this prompt does not accept standard input
    from a `|` pipeline; this is intentional to leave it intact for the
    interpreted script. In non-interactive contexts, instead append to
    `unix_windows.tab` in advance:

        $ echo /bin/python\tpython.exe >> unix_windows.tab
        $ echo Input of the standard variety | my_script.py

    interrupt signals may not propogate during this prompt; to abort simply
    enter an empty value.

Arguments
    -a [file extension]
        Associate wshbang (as in older Windows versions). This will prompt to
        elevate a process, per UAC settings. Without a file extension, this will
        register the script & proper invocation. If a file extension is given,
        it will additional associate to that particular filetype. Include the
        dot character, eg `.ext`! To associate with plain files -- those with no
        extension, pass the dot character alone `.`.

🦝
